The last time we saw Philip,
we learned about energy
and how it was converted.
When he dropped the paint bucket.
Philip had to use energy to climb back
down the ladder and get new paint,
so he is not pushing the wheelbarrow
as fast as he did earlier,
even though he is doing the same
amount of work as before and thus
using the same amount of energy.
The rate he is working at is slower.
This means he has less power than before.
Power is the rate at which work is done.
We calculate it by dividing the work
done in joules by the time taken
in seconds to complete the work.
The unit of power is joules per second.
It is also known as the what.
W If Phillip took 20 seconds to move the
wheelbarrow and did 1000 joules of work,
his power is 50 watts.
Let's say Phillip takes one minute to carry
the 2K bucket up the five metre ladder.
What is his power?
First we calculate the work done.
Gravity exerts 10 Newton
per kilogram on the bucket,
so the weight of the bucket is 20 Newton.
The work done is 100 joules.
We divide that by the time taken,
which is one minute in order
to find Phillips power.
But remember to measure power
you must use seconds,
so we convert the time
in minutes into seconds.
Therefore,
Phillips Power is 100 / 60,
so his power is 1.67 watts,
and that's how you measure power.
You may have seen that electrical
objects also have what's written on them.
This is called the power rating
and it shows the rate at which
the machine does work.
Obviously this drill has more
power than Phillip did when he
carried the paint up the ladder,
and that's why we use machines
because they can exert more
power than what our bodies can.
Some machines are so powerful that
they are measured in horsepower.
1 horsepower is 750 watts.
The terms Watt and horsepower were
developed by Scottish engineer
James Watt in the 1700s.
He used the term to compare the power
of horses with that of steam engines.
Looks like Phillip needs to find a new house.
At least he understands work,
energy and power though.